Register of the Myers G. Lowman papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Myers G. Lowman papers
1920-1969
67019
Hoover Institution Archives
99 manuscript boxes, 1 card file box, 11 envelopes, 3 motion picture film reels (42.6 linear feet)
Correspondence, memoranda, pamphlets, photographs, motion picture film, sound recordings, and clippings relating to communism and other leftist movements, the civil rights movement, and anti-communism, primarily in the United States.
Lowman, Myers G.
Access
Boxes 92-93 closed. The remainder of the collection is open for research.
Use copies of some sound recordings in this collection are available for immediate access. To listen to other sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1967.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Executive secretary, Circuit Riders, Inc.
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, memoranda, pamphlets, photographs, motion picture film, sound recordings, and clippings relating to communism and other leftist movements, the civil rights movement, and anti-communism, primarily in the United States.
Circuit Riders, Inc.; Anti-communist movements--United States.; Civil rights--United States.; Communism--United States.; Motion pictures.; Audiotapes.
- Subject File, 1920-1964 (Boxes 1-85)
  Scope and Contents note
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports, notes, pamphlets, clippings, and printed matter relating to communism in the United States collected by Lowman as Executive Secretary of Circuit Riders, Inc., arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Academic freedom (Box 1)
  - Acheson, Dean
  - Adamic, Louis
  - Addresses - Patriotic
  - Aderholdt, Grover
  - Advertising Federation of America
  - Africa
  - Air Force manual
  - Airlines
  - Alabama
  - Alabama Christian Movement for Human Rights
  - Alaska Mental Health Act
  - Alien Deportation and Exclusion League
  - All-American Conference to Combat Communism
  - "Allegiance to the United Nations of an American Citizen"
  - Allentown Anti-Communist Society
  - Allied Faiths Council
  - Allied Youth, Inc.
  - Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America
  - America First Committee
  - America's Future, Inc.
  - American Anti-Communist Foundation (Box 2)
  - American Asian Educational Exchange
  - American Association for Economic Freedom
  - American Association of Scientific Workers
  - American Association of University Professors
  - American Bar Association
  - American Brotherhood of Christian Congress
  - American China Policy Association
  - American Christian Union
  - American Civic Alliance
  - American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU)
    - General
    - Pamphlets and leaflets
    - Pamphlets and leaflets (Box 3)
    - Annual reports (Box 4)
  - American Coalition (Box 5)
  - American Coalition of New York
  - American Coalition of Patriotic Societies
  - American Committee for Democracy and Intellectual Freedom
  - American Committee for Indonesian Independence
  - American Committee for Non-Participation in Japanese Aggression
  - American Committee for the Defense of Leon Trotsky
  - American Committee for the Protection of Foreign Born
  - American Congress for Peace and Democracy
  - American Council for Social Justice
  - American Council of Christian Churches
  - American Council of Christian Laymen
  - American Defenders
  - American Defenders for Freedom, Inc.
  - American Defense Society, Inc.
  - American Discussion League, Inc.
  - American Education Association
  - American Enterprise Association
  - American Factfinders Institute
  - American Flag Committee
  - American Friends Service Committee
  - American Fund for Public Service
  - American Good Government Society
  - American Gospel Crusaders
  - American Guild for German Cultural Freedom
  - American Institute
  - American Institute of Fraternal Citizenship
  - American Institute of Patriotic Education
  - American Investors Union
  - American Jewish Committee
  - American Jewish League Against Communism
  - American Labor Party
  - American League Against Communism
  - American League Against War and Fascism
  - American League Against War and Fascism (Box 6)
  - American League for Peace and Democracy
  - American League for Tolerance
  - American League to Combat Anti-Semitism
  - American Legion - Firing Line
  - American Legion Auxiliary
  - American Minute Men
  - American National Party
  - American National Patriotic Society
  - American Nationalist Party
  - American Nationalists
  - American Negro Labor Congress
  - American Neutrality, Inc.
  - American Newspaper Guild
  - American Patriot
  - American Patriots, Inc.
  - American Patriots Against Foreign Wars, Inc.
  - American Patriotic Women
  - American Peace Movement
  - American Peace Society
  - American People's Mobilization
  - American Planning and Civic Association
  - American Political Science Association
  - American Public Welfare
  - American Radio Telegraphists' Association
  - American Rangers
  - American Relief Ship for Spain
  - American School of Christian Democracy
  - American Society, The
  - American Society for Cultural Relations with Russia (USSR)
  - American Sponsoring Committee Against Nazi Outrages
  - American Student Union
  - American Taxpayers League
  - American Tolerance Committee
  - American Trade Union Delegation to the Soviet Union
  - American Union for Concerted Peace Efforts
  - American Union for Righteous Government
  - American Vigilant Intelligence Federation
  - American Veterans Association
  - American Womanhood Society
  - American Workers Party
  - American Youth Congress (Box 7)
  - American Youth Council
  - American Youth for Democracy
  - American Youth Foundation
  - Americana Group
  - Americanism Federation
  - Americans
  - Americans All
  - Americans for Democratic Action
  - Ameringer, Siegfried
  - Amter, Israel
  - Anderson, Paul Y.
  - Anti-Communism Society
  - Anti-Communist Federation of America
  - Anti-Defamation League
  - Anti-Semitism
  - Arab National League
  - Arizona Peace Officers Association
  - Arnold, Thurman
  - Arthur, Chester
  - Artists Front to Win the War
  - Arts, Sciences, and Professions for May Day
  - Association of Books for Children
  - Atheism - Communist inspired (Box 8)
  - Atlantic Alliance, 1962 (Box 9)
  - Atlantic Charter, 1945
  - Atlantic Institute, 1961
  - Atlantic Union Committee for World Government
  - Attack on State Department's exclusion of foreign communists
  - Baldwin, Roger Nash
  - Baltimore
  - Bang-Jensen
  - Barth, Joseph
  - Bates, Daisey
  - Batt, William Loren
  - Beale, Thomas (Sr.)
  - Beall, Hayes
  - Bennett, John C.
  - Benson, Dr. George
  - Bentley, Elizabeth
  - Berlin
  - Bernays, Edward L.
  - Berry, Abner W.
  - Berry, Theodore
  - Bethune, Mary McLeod
  - Bichowsky, F. Russell
  - Biddle, Francis B.
  - Bi-Partisan Foreign Policy
  - Blake, Mildred M. R. (Box 10)
  - Blankenhorn, Heber
  - Blanshard, Paul
  - Boaz, Franz
  - Bohlen, Charles E.
  - Books - how selected for libraries
  - Book Union, Inc.
  - Borders, Karl
  - Boy Rangers of America
  - Boy Scouts
  - Boys' Athletic League
  - Boys' Republic
  - Braden, Ann and Carl
  - Brainwashing in high schools
  - Brameld, Theodore
  - Brandeis, Justice
  - Brauer, Max
  - Braunstein, Baruch
  - Bricker Amendment
  - Bridges, Harry
  - Bridges and Strecker
  - British Israel
  - Britt, George
  - Brodsky, Joseph
  - Bromley, Ernest (Box 11)
  - Brotherhood
  - Browder, Earl
  - Brown, William Montgomery
  - Browne, Conrad
  - Browne, Karl
  - Brownell, Herbert
  - Bruere, Robert
  - Brustat. A. M.
  - Bryan, Julien
  - Bryant, Steward F.
  - Bullitt, Ambassador
  - Bunche, Ralph
  - "Bund"
  - Bureau of University Travel
  - Cabot, Henry B. (Box 12)
  - Campbell, Byron
  - Canadian Intelligence Service
  - Canfield, Cass
  - Cannon, Walter B.
  - "Capsule"
  - CARE
  - Carey, Sophia
  - Caribbean
  - Carnegie, Andrew
  - Carter, Boake
  - Carter, John F.
  - Catholic Association for International Peace
  - Celler, Emanuel
  - Central America
  - Chafee, Zachariah
  - Chamberlain, Joseph P.
  - Chapelle, Winifred
  - Chase, Stuart
  - Chicago Committee to Defend the Bill of Rights
  - China - Taiwan
  - Christian Social Action Leader's Handbook
  - Christian Social Action Manual
  - Christian Youth Council of North America
  - Christmas celebrations
  - Church and churchmen (Box 13)
  - Church League of Industrial Democracy
  - Circuit Riders, Inc. (Box 14)
  - Circuit Riders, Inc. (Box 15)
  - Citizens Committee to Free Earl Browder
  - Civil defense
  - Civil rights movements
  - Civil Service Commission
  - Clark, Reuben
  - Clement, Rufus
  - Clergymen on War and Economic Injustice
  - Clergymen's letter to FDR in defense of the Communist Party
  - Coe, John M. (Box 16)
  - Co-existence
  - Colleges
    - Hunter
    - Progressive education
    - Sarah Lawrence, Smith
    - Yale, Wisconsin University
    - Columbia University
  - Commager, H. S.
  - Commission on Christian Social Concerns
  - Committee Against Intolerance in America
  - Committee for Conscientious Objectors
  - Committee for Constitutional Government
  - Committee for Cultural Freedom
  - Committee for Peaceful Alternatives to the Atlantic Pact
  - Committee of Christian Laymen, Inc.
  - Committee of One Million
  - Committee on Pan-American Policy
  - "Common Sense"
  - Communism
  - Communism (Boxes 17-19)
  - Communist - Anti, propaganda (Box 20)
  - Communist deception in the churches
  - Communist controlled youth movements and infiltration of youth
  - Communist exhibits and individuals (Box 21)
  - "Communist Fronts" -- News coverage of Lowman's speech at Pascagoula, Mississippi, 1966 March 15
  - Communist Party
  - Communist Party - USA
  - Communist Party - USA (Box 22)
  - Communist propaganda
  - Communist publications
  - Communist publications (Box 23)
  - Communist strategy to promote racial hatred
  - Community Chests and Councils of America
  - Conference for Progressive Labor Action (CPLA)
  - Congress, 1963
  - Connally Amendment
  - Constitution
  - Cook, Claire
  - Corcordan, Thomas G.
  - Correspondence - miscellaneous
  - Cory, Herbert Ellsworth
  - Coughlin, Daniel
  - Coughlin, Father
  - Counts, George S.
  - "Counter Attack"
  - Coyle, Albert F.
  - Craft, Blake (Rev.)
  - Cramer, Lawrence
  - Crane, Henry Hitt (Box 24)
  - Crane, Jasper E.
  - Creigh, Thomas
  - Cronbach, Abraham
  - Cutler, Robert
  - Cuba - Blockade, 1962 October
  - Cybercultural research
  - Dahlberg, Edwin T.
  - Davis, Forest
  - Davis, Jerome
  - Dean, Arthur
  - De Gaulle, Charles
  - Desegregation, Coordinating Committee of the New Orleans Committee for the Study of
  - Dewey, John
  - Dies Committee (Box 25)
  - Dies, Martin
  - Dilling, Albert Wallwich
  - Dilling, Elizabeth
  - Dillon, Douglas
  - Disarmament
  - Dodd, Martha
  - Dogett, Caxton
  - Dobley, Dorothy
  - Dombrowski, Jim (Director - Southern Conference Educational Fund, Inc.)
  - Douglas, William O.
  - Drugs - Non-medical use
  - Dulles, John Foster
  - DuBois, W. E. B. (Box 26)
  - Dunjee, Roscoe
  - DuPont, Henry
  - Eaton, Cyrus (Box 27)
  - Edmiston, John
  - Edmiston, Martha
  - Education (Box 28)
  - Education (Box 29)
  - Educators with communist front affiliations
    - A-J (Boxes 30-32)
    - J-K (Box 33)
    - K-L (Box 34)
    - M-N (Box 35)
    - Miscellaneous
  - "L'Eglise et le culte en U.R.S.S."
  - Einstein, Albert
  - Eisenhower, Dwight David
  - Electoral College
  - Emergency Civil Liberties Committee
  - Ensley, Bishop Gerald (Box 36)
  - Episcopal Church
  - Equal Rights Amendment
  - Executive Powers, 1963
  - Fabian Socialism
  - Fascism (including Nazism)
  - FBI (Box 37)
  - Federal Council of Churches
  - Federal Theater Project
  - Federal Union World
  - Federation of Former Communists, Inc.
  - Fellowship of Reconciliation
  - Ferre, Nels
  - Finletter, Thomas K.
  - Fisher, Dorothy C.
  - Flag, American (Box 38)
  - Florida
  - Florida Legislative Investigating Committee
  - Ford Foundation
  - Foreign Policy Association
  - Foundations
  - Foundations (Box 39)
  - Frank, Glenn
  - Frankfurter, Felix
  - Friends of Democracy (Box 40)
  - Friends of Public Schools, bulletins, 1940
  - Friends of the Soviet Union
  - Fritchman, Stephen H.
  - Fulbright, J. W.
  - Fund for the Republic
  - Gara, Larry
  - General agreements on tariffs and trade
  - Ginder, Richard
  - Gitlow, Benjamin
  - Globalism
  - Goldenweiser, Emanuel A.
  - Goldsmith, Arthur
  - Gomillion, Charles G.
  - Goslin, Willard E.
  - Gould, Joseph S.
  - Graham, Marcus
  - Grass Roots League, Inc.
  - Grey, John H.
  - Griggs, Edward Howard
  - Gross, Ernest
  - Guerard, Albert
  - Hammerstein, Oscar II
  - Harkness, Georgia
  - Harriman, Mrs. J. B.
  - Harris, M. Lafayette
  - Harvard - Sex questionnaires
  - Hathaway, Clarence Albert
  - Hawaiian Islands
  - Hayden, Thomas
  - Hayes, Carlton Joseph Huntley
  - Hays, Arthur Garfield
  - Hays, Brooks
  - Hazzard, Lewell B. (Box 41)
  - Headlines
  - Healey, Raymond Joseph
  - Hearst, William Randolph
  - Heller, Abraham Aaron
  - Helstin, Ralph
  - Hemingway, Ernest
  - Herrick, Robert
  - Herring, Hubert
  - Hessler, William H.
  - Hetzel, Ralph Dorn (Jr.)
  - Hicks, Granville
  - High, Stanley
  - Highlander Folk School
  - Hill, Charles Leander
  - Hindus, Maurice
  - Hinrichs, A. Ford
  - Hobson, Henry Wise
  - Holly, William H.
  - Holmes, John Haynes
  - Hooker, Edith
  - Hoover, J. Edgar
  - Hopkins, Harry (Box 42)
  - House Committee on Un-American Activities
    General note
    See also box 95
  - Houston
  - Howe, Frederick C.
  - Hughes, Langston
  - Human Events
  - Humanism
  - Hungarian Freedom Fighters Federation, Inc.
  - Hunt, H. L.
  - Hurley, Ruby
  - Hyde, Homer
  - Ickes, Harold (Box 43)
  - Ilma, Viola
  - Immigration and naturalization
  - Independence Foundation, Inc.
  - Ingvoldstad, Fred W.
  - Institute of Pacific Relations
  - Intercollegiate Socialist Society Report, 1962
  - International Committee for Political Prisoners
  - International Court of Justice
  - International Finance - McFadden, 1930
  - International Labor Defense
  - International labor organizations
  - International trade organizations
  - International Workers Order, Inc.
  - Jackson, Edgar N.
  - Jackson, Gardner
  - Jackson, James C.
  - Japan
  - Japanese Peace Treaty
  - Jehovah's Witnesses
  - Jenner, William (Box 44)
  - Jewish National Workers Alliance
  - Jews
  - Johnson, Hewlett (Box 45)
  - Johnson, Hugh S.
  - Johnson, Manning
  - Johnson, William R.
  - Johnston, Eric
  - Jones, John Paul
  - Jordan, Racey
  - Kagawa
  - Kamp, Joseph
  - Katanga
  - Kaye, Danny
  - Keep America Committee
  - Kellock, Katherine
  - Kelly, Florence
  - Kennedy, Joseph P.
  - Kent, Rockwell
  - Keynes, John Maynard
  - King, Martin Luther
  - Kirov, Sergei M.
  - Kohlberg, Alfred
  - Kollontai, Alexandra
  - Korea
  - Kornfeder, Joseph Z.
  - Koussevitsky, Serge
  - Kropotkin, Peter
  - Krumm, John M.
  - Langer, Senator (Box 46)
  - Langford, Howard
  - Lansbury, George
  - Laski, Harold
  - Lattimore, Owen
  - Laubach, Frank
  - Lawrence, David
  - Laws, Clarence
  - Lawson, James
  - League for Industrial Democracy
  - League of Women Voters
  - LeHand, Margaret
  - Leiserson, William Morris
  - Lerner, Max
  - "Liberal Papers"
  - Libraries - U.S.
  - Lie, Trygve
  - Lincoln, Murry D.
  - Lindbergh, Charles
  - Loomer, Bernard M.
  - Lorch, Lee (Box 47)
  - Lothian, Lord
  - Louisiana Joint Legislative Committee
  - Louisiana Legislative Committee, 1957
  - Louisiana, list of Communist Party members
  - Lovestone, Jay
  - Lovitt, Sidney
  - Loyalty Oaths - Student loans
  - Lutheran Church - Arizona
  - MacArthur, Douglas (Box 48)
  - Mack, Julian
  - Mackay, John
  - MacLeish, Archibald
  - Mailing lists
  - Mallory, Willie Mae
  - Malone, George
  - Manly, Basil
  - Mann, Thomas
  - Marcantonio, Vito
  - Marshall, George C.
  - Marshall, Robert
  - Martinoff, Co. Alexander P.
  - Matthews, J. B. (Box 49)
  - Matusow, Harvey
  - McCarran Act
  - McCarthy, Joseph
  - McConnell, Dorothy (Box 50)
  - McConnell, Francis
  - McCrackin, M.
  - McGowan, Edward F.
  - McGregor, A. H.
  - McMichael, Jack
  - McNutt, Waldo
  - Meachaw, Stewart
  - Melby, E. O.
  - Melish, William Howard
  - Mena, Felix Roldan
  - Mencken, Henry Louis
  - Methodist Church
  - Methodist clergy with communist front affiliations (Box 51)
  - Methodist Federation for Social Action (Box 52)
  - Methodist Federation for Social Action (Box 53)
  - Mexico
  - Meyer, Cord (Jr.)
  - Middle East - Eisenhower Doctrine
  - The Militant (Trotskyite), 1950
  - Military training
  - Miller, Clyde
  - Minor, Robert
  - Mississippi Legislative Investigating Committee
  - Moley, Raymond
  - Montgomery, Donald E.
  - Mooney, Tom
  - Mooney - Billings case
  - Moos, Mrs.
  - Morley, Felix
  - "Moscow News,", 1936 September
  - Movies
  - Muelder, Walter
  - Mumford, Lewis
  - Munitions
  - Muir, Jean
  - Murrow, Ed
  - Mussolini
  - Myers, James
  - Nash, Vernon (Box 54)
  - National Anthem Bill, 1962
  - NAACP - "Committee of 100" - with communist front affiliations
  - National Citizens Committee
  - National Committee to Abolish the House Committee on Un-American Activities
  - National Coordinating Committee to End the War in Vietnam
  - National Council for Prevention of War (Box 55)
  - National Council of American-Soviet Friendship
  - National Council of Churches
  - National Council of the Churches of Christ in the USA
  - National defense
  - National Defense Commission
  - National Economic Council, Inc.
  - National Federation for Constitutional Liberties
  - National Labor Board (Box 56)
  - National Lawyers Guild
  - National Religion and Labor Foundation
  - "National Republic"
  - National Sacramento Appeal Committee
  - National Science Foundation
  - National Urban League, The
  - Nationalist Party bulletin
  - NATO and SACLANT flags
  - Nearing, Scott (Box 57)
  - Negro college presidents
  - Negroes
  - Neutrality
  - New Deal - criticism, speeches, articles
  - "New Deal" - individuals (Box 58)
  - New Party, Committee for the Formation of the
  - New York State Economic Council
  - "News and Views"
  - Niebuhr, Reinhold
  - Nye
  - O'Brien, Robert L. (Box 59)
  - O'Day, Mrs. Caroline
  - Occult
  - Oppenheimer, J. Robert
  - Oregon Federation for Social Action
  - Organizations
    - College
    - Congress, creed
    - D-F (Box 60)
    - G-I
    - J-M
    - Methodist "pink" and "red" (Box 61)
    - National
    - National Council
    - Nature
    - O-T
    - Radical (Box 62)
    - "To invite"
    - U-Z
  - Oxford Group (Box 63)
  - Oxford Union
  - Oxnam, G. Bromley
  - Pacifism (Box 64)
    - General
    - Organizations
  - Page, Kirby
  - Paradise, James C.
  - Parent Teachers' Association (PTA) (Box 65)
  - Parker, Andrew Morgan
  - Paton
  - Patriots
  - Patton, James G.
  - Pauling, Linus
  - Peace campaigns
  - Pegler, Westbrook
  - Pelley Publications
  - Pennypacker, Anna M.
  - Periodicals and publications
    - General
    - Philip Dru, Woodrow Wilson (Box 66)
  - Pershing, George
  - Peters, Paul
  - Philander Smith College
  - Pickett, Clarence E.
  - Pike, Bishop James
  - Polakov, Walter N.
  - Poling, Daniel A.
  - Popkin, Martin E.
  - Powell, Noble C.
  - Powell-Schuman Defense Fund
  - Presbyterian Church
  - Prince, Frank
  - Prior, Leon O.
  - Projects
  - Propaganda analysis
  - Protest movements
  - Protestant clergy with communist front affiliations (Box 67)
  - Protestant Episcopal Church (Box 68)
  - Protestant Episcopal Church (Box 69)
  - PWA (WPA, NRA, TVA)
  - Rabbis with communist front affiliations (Box 70)
  - Randolph, A. Philip (Box 71)
  - Rankin, Jeanette
  - Rauschenbush, N. Stephen
  - Red Alert
  - Red China
  - "Red Fog" - Published by the National Patriotic League (Box 72)
  - "Red Treason in Hollywood,", 1949
  - Religion
    - General
    - Atheism
    - Baptists
    - Catholics
    - Fellowship of Faiths
    - Social action
  - Religion and Labor Foundation (Box 73)
  - Religious Freedom Committee
  - Reuben, William A.
  - Reuther, Walter
  - Revelation Baptist Church
  - Reynolds, Robert N.
  - Richberg, Donald
  - Right to Work Committee
  - Robinson, James H.
  - Roenick, Nicholas K.
  - Rogers, Donald I.
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D.
  - Roosevelt, James (Box 74)
  - Roselli, Bruno
  - Rosenfeld, Kurt
  - Rosenbergs
  - Ross, Edward A.
  - ROTC
    - Chicago publications, high schools
    - Universities and colleges
  - Rubenstein, Harry H.
  - Rugg, Harold
  - Russell, Bertrand (Box 75)
  - Rustin, Bayard
  - Sabath - Steele controversy (Box 76)
  - Saposs, David J.
  - Schneiderman, Rose
  - Schreiber, Julius
  - Schuman, Frederick
  - Schwarz, Fred
  - Schwimmer, Rosika
  - SDS
  - Seeger, Peter
  - Segregation
  - Sharlau, Gene
  - Sharp, Dudley
  - Siegrist, Robert
  - Sifton, Paul
  - Smith, Alson J.
  - Smith, Benjamin
  - Smythe, Edward J.
  - Socialism
  - Socialist Commonwealth of America
  - Socialist Labor Party
  - Socialist Party of America (USA)
  - Socialist Workers Party of Germany
  - Sockman, Ralph Washington
  - Sokolsky
  - Sons of the American Revolution
  - Southern Christian Leadership Conference
  - Southern Conference Educational Fund
  - Southern Conference for Human Welfare
  - Southern Methodist Church
  - Southern Regional Council, Inc.
  - Spallholtz reports, 1936 (Box 77)
  - Spallholtz expense accounts
  - Speeches, statements, resolutions, etc. by Lowman
  - Spivak, John L.
  - Sporborg, Mrs. W. D.
  - Spotlight - Westchester County
  - Sproul, Marion E.
  - Status of forces
  - Steele, Walter
  - Sterling (administration)
  - Stern, David
  - Stevens, Thelma
  - Stewart, Donald O.
  - Stewart, Maxwell
  - Stokely, Wilma Dykeman
  - Strong, Anna Louise
  - Stuber, Stanley I. (Box 78)
  - Student Peace Union
  - Subversive Activities Control Board
  - Subversive organizations, Guide to
  - Swing, Raymond
  - Taft, Senator "Bob"
  - Taiwan (Formosa)
  - Tariff
  - Taylor, Gardner
  - Tax-exempt foundations
  - Theatre Guild
  - Thompson, Dorothy
  - Thompson, John B.
  - Tilly, Dorothy
  - Tisler, Frantisek
  - Tornoff (alias, Turrou), Leon
  - Trade agreements
  - Travel to Russia, 1934
  - Trevor, John B.
  - Trotsky, Leon (Box 79)
  - Trueblood, Elton
  - Tucker, Harry St. George
  - Tucker, Luther
  - Tugwell, Rexford G.
  - Turnipseed, A. L.
  - Tyler, Gus
  - UNESCO
  - Union of Soviet Socialist Republics and Satellites
  - Union Theological Seminary
  - Unitarian - Universalist clergy with communist front affiliations
  - Unitarian - Universalist clergy with communist front affiliations (Box 80)
  - United Nations
  - United States defense support in Western Europe, 1952-1953
  - United States National Student Association (USNSA)
  - United World Federalists
  - Untermyer, Samuel (Box 81)
  - Uphaus, Willard
  - Urey, Harold C.
  - Van Doren, Carl
  - "Vanguard"
  - Van Kleeck, Mary
  - Van Paassen, Pierre
  - Veterans of Foreign Wars
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade
  - Viereck, G. S.
  - Vietnam
  - Villard, Oswald G.
  - Voorhis, Jerry H.
  - Voronaeff, Paul
  - Warbasse, James P.
  - Ward, Harry F.
  - Washington, D.C.
  - Watson, Goodwin
  - Weber, Charles